抽象数据类型是一个实例
Abstract data types are an instance
软件工程的一般原理
of a general principle in software engineering, which
有很多名字的意思略有不同。
goes by many names with slightly different shades of meaning.
以下是我们为这个想法使用的一些名称。
Here are some of the names we use for this idea.
抽象意味着省略或
Abstraction means omitting or the
隐藏一些细节，但更简单的更高层次的想法。
hiding little details, but the simpler higher level idea.
模块化意味着您想划分
Modularity means you want to divide
将系统分成若干个组件或模块，每个组件或模块
the system into components or modules, each of which
可以设计，实现，测试，推理，
can be designed, implemented, tested, reasoned about,
与系统其他部分分开使用。
and re-used separately from the rest of the system.
封装是相似的，但是
Encapsulation is similar, but that's
关于在每个模块周围建造墙壁就像一个硬壳
about building walls around each module like a hard shell
或者是一个密封舱
or a capsule so that the module is
对自己的内部行为负责。
responsible for its own internal behavior.
系统其他部分的错误
And bugs in other parts of the system
不能破坏内部行为的完整性。
can't damage the integrity of that internal behavior.
信息隐藏就像抽象。
Information hiding is like abstraction.
它是关于隐藏模块实现的细节
It's about hiding the details of a module's implementation
从系统的其他部分，以便这些细节可以
from the rest of the system so that those details can
以后更改而不更改
be changed later without changing
系统的其他部分。
the rest of the system.
最后，关注点的分离
And finally, separation of concerns
意味着对你的系统做一个特性
means making a feature of your system, which
可能被称为一个问题，责任
might be called a concern, the responsibility
一个模块而不是广泛传播
of a single module rather than spreading it widely
在你的程序中。
across your program.
现在，作为一名软件工程师
Now, as a software engineer, it's
了解这些术语很重要，因为
important to know these terms because you'll actually
经常碰到他们或他们的变种。
run into them or variations of them frequently.
但所有这些想法的根本目的
But the fundamental purpose of all of these ideas
是为了实现我们所关心的三个重要属性
is to help achieve the three important properties we care
大约在6.005年-安全，易于理解，
about in the 6.005-- safety from bugs, ease of understanding,
准备好改变。
and readiness for change.
抽象数据类型将帮助我们做到这一点。
And abstract data types are going to help us do that.
现在，在计算的早期，
Now, in the early days of computing,
一种内置类型的编程语言
a programming language came with built-in types
像整数、布尔字符串和内置过程
like integers, Boolean strings, and built-in procedures
比如输入和输出。
like for input and output.
用户可以定义自己的过程。
Users could define their own procedures.
这就是大型程序的构建方式。
That's how large programs were built.
但他们并没有提供设施
But they didn't really provide facilities
用于定义新类型。
for defining new types.
软件开发的重大进展
So a major advance in software development
抽象类型的概念是否允许--
was the idea of abstract types allowing--
设计一种编程语言，允许用户定义类型为
designing a programming language to allow user-defined types as
好。
well.
这个想法出自许多研究人员的工作，特别是
This idea came out of the work of many researchers, notably
Dahl发明了Simula，Tony Hoare发明了许多
Dahl, who invented Simula, and Tony Hoare, who developed many
我们使用的技术
of the techniques that we're using
为了解释抽象类型，
to reason about the abstract types,
还有大卫·帕纳斯，他创造了信息隐藏这个词
and David Parnas, who coined the term information hiding
首先阐述了组织的概念
and first articulated the idea of organizing
围绕它们封装的秘密编程模块。
program modules around the secrets they encapsulated.
在麻省理工学院，芭芭拉·利斯科夫和约翰·古塔格
Here at MIT, Barbara Liskov and John Guttag
在抽象类型的规范方面做了开创性的工作
did seminal work in the specification of abstract types
以及编程语言对它们的支持。
and in programming languages' support for them.
他们还开发了原始的6170，
They also developed the original 6170,
这是本课程的前身。
which is the predecessor to this course.
芭芭拉·利斯科夫获得了图灵奖，
Barbara Liskov earned the Turing Award,
计算机科学相当于诺贝尔奖
which is the computer science equivalent of the Nobel Prize
因为她对抽象类型的研究。
for her work on abstract types.
所以这是一个重要的想法。
So this is an important idea.
现在，抽象数据的数据抽象的关键思想
Now, the key idea of data abstraction of abstract data
类型是一个类型只具有特征
types is that a type is characterized only
通过对其执行的操作--
by the operations that can perform on it--
您可以对其执行操作，而不是通过数据结构
you can perform on it, and not by the data structure
你用来代表它。
you use to represent it.
例如，一个数字，一个整数，
So for example, a number, an integer for instance,
是你可以加和乘的东西。
is something that you can add and multiply.
这些是我们可以对一个数字做的操作。
Those are the operations we can do on a number.
绳子是你能做的
A string is something that you can
获取concatenate和take子字符串并获取
take concatenate and take substrings and get
单个字符。
individual characters out of.
这些是可以对字符串执行的操作。
Those are the operations you can do on a string.
布尔值是可以否定的，等等。
A Boolean is something you can negate, and so on.
所以在某种意义上，用户已经可以定义
So in a sense, users could already define, even
在早期的编程语言中，
in those early programming languages,
他们可以通过创建记录数据来定义自己的类型
they could define their own types by creating a record data
类型，例如，具有日期、月份和，
type, for example, that had integer fields for day, month,
然后定义
and year and then define procedures that were
对那个类型的操作。
the operations on that type.
那么是什么让抽象类型变得新奇和不同
So what made abstract types new and different
这是对行动的关注。
was this focus on operations.
类型的用户不需要
The user of the type would not need
担心它的价值
to worry about how its values were
事实上，我们可以避免
actually stored and, in fact, would be able to avoid
就看这个了。
depending on that.
就像程序员可以忽略的那样
In the same way that a programmer can ignore
编译器——编译器实际上存储
the compiler-- compiler actually stores
像整数这样的原始类型
primitive types like integers, all that matters
是什么操作以及这些操作的规格。
is what operations there are and the specs of those operations.
现在，在Java中，就像在许多现代编程语言中一样，
Now, in Java, as in many modern programming languages,
内置类型和用户定义类型之间的分离
the separation between built-in types and user-defined types
实际上有点模糊。
is actually a bit blurry.
java.lang包中有一些类，如capital
There are classes in the java.lang package like capital
I整数和大写I布尔值，在技术上是
I Integer and capital I Boolean that are technically
被认为是内置的。
considered built-in.
但不管你是否重视所有的收藏
But whether you regard all of the collection
内置java.util中的类不太清楚，也不太清楚
classes in java.util as built-in is less clear and not very
无论如何都很重要。
important anyway.
Java使问题进一步复杂化
Java complicates the issue further
通过具有不均匀的原始类型
by having primitive types that are not even
像int和Boolean这样的对象。
objects like int and Boolean.
这组类型，原始类型，
This set of types, primitive types,
用户无法扩展。
cannot be extended by the user.
我们只能创建新类，而不能创建新的基元类型。
We can only create new classes, not new primitive types.